# AKEEM BRISCO

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

https://akeemthedream.com

• https://github.com/akeembrisco

**(289)-600-9509** 

\* www.linkedin.com/in/akeem-brisco-6b3b47128

### **SUMMARY**

Passionate Web Developer with 3+ years of experience crafting engaging and responsive web applications. Strong Computer Science background (University of Toronto) fuels my ability to develop across diverse platforms – from seamless mobile experiences to optimized applications for Xbox and Smart TV. React is expertise is coupled with a versatile skillset including Vue.is, WordPress, and various coding languages, ensuring I can adapt to and conquer your unique project needs. Let's collaborate and build something amazing together!

### **EXPERIENCE**

Wijs – Software (Vue) Developer

October 2023 – Present

- Led front-end development for web & mobile apps, crafting a seamless user experience and driving platform adoption.
- Elevated platform functionality and aesthetics: implemented reusable components, fixed visual bugs, and delivered new features.
- Championed collaboration and knowledge sharing: leveraged a diverse tech stack (Frontend: Docker, Laravel, Vue.js, SCSS, Bootstrap; Collaboration: Bitbucket, Jira, Figma, Slack) and mentored developers to strengthen team capabilities.

**Accedo** – Web & Software Developer

April 2021 – April 2023

- Managed and developed 20+ responsive web apps for 32,000+ monthly users, collaborating with marketing and sales to leverage mobile growth.
- Delivered exceptional user experiences. Resolved critical bugs, optimized web app performance, and engineered a UWP app for Xbox One (C++, HTML/JavaScript, .NET).
- Promoted strong collaboration. Identified and solved complex technical challenges with cross-functional teams, including project architecture and future planning.

### **EDUCATION**

**University of Toronto** 

- Honours Bachelor of Science (HBSc)
- Computer Science, Mathematics, Communication Culture Information & Technology

## APPLICATIONS AND PROJECTS

Sensical – Software Developer

April 2021 – April 2023

Front-end developer for Sensical (https://www.sensical.tv), a free streaming service for kids, fostering social, emotional, and cognitive development. Contributed to the seamless integration of mobile-friendly features and optimized user interfaces to enhance overall user experience.

ReactJS, SCSS, MEAN, HTML, Python, CSS, Jira, Agile, Bitbucket, GitHub

Wijs – Vue Developer

October 2023 – Present

Wijs (https://wijs.ca) is the next-level Health & Safety Management solution. Wijs goes beyond basic digital systems to automate and connect your H&S and save you hours of work.

Vue JS, HTML, CSS, Laravel, Bootstrap, Docker, GitHub, Slack, Jira

#### **SKILLS**

- Front-End Development: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Back-End & APIs: NodeJS, Python & RESTful APIs
- Agile & DevOps: Proficient in Agile methodologies & familiar with CI/CD pipelines
- Collaboration: Utilize Jira, GitHub, Bitbucket for communication & code management